Guide to the John Reps papers, [ca. 1865-2006],
Reps, John papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
John Reps papers, [ca. 1865-2006], [ca. 1940-2006] (bulk)
15-2-1101
John William. Reps
ca. 54.3 cubic feet.
1 reel negative microfilm.
Photographs
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Drafts, resource materials, proofs and correspondence concerning Reps's book, Monumental Washington, ca.1967; first drafts, final manuscripts and galley proofs of The Making of Urban America, ca.1965 and Town Planning in Frontier America, ca.1968. Also, five photographs, ca.1865: three albumen prints of the Rochester flood; and two gelatin prints of the Sibley fire, Rochester, New York, collected by Professor Reps. Also notes on Competitors Australian Federal Capital Competition for the book Canberra, 1912; correspondence pertaining to Saint Louis Illustrated; and publications and lectures by Reps. Files for CRP 462.
Research materials and notes for a projected book about planning in the Southeastern United States.
Also, scrapbooks and albums compiled from various trips taken by Professor and Mrs. Reps, and an album from the 2001 symposium commemorating Professor Reps's 50th anniversary at Cornell.
Notes, correspondence, drafts, etc. relating to John Caspar Wild: Painter and Printmaker of Nineteenth-century Urban America, a catalogue raisonné, by John Reps, published by the Missouri Historical Society Press, 2006.
Photographs and articles, also a CD (CD-1387) relating to Gilmore Clarke.
Personal items include photographs; travel diary from England, 1947; interviews with UK planners, 1950-1951 and a 1994 article; negatives of views of French bastides (new towns) used in an exhibition; color transparencies of Cornell views, summer 1986; file "How Lewis Mumford Never Came to Cornell," 1965-1970; correspondence about St. Louis Illustrated, 1985; file on Alex McLean/Landslides for Cities of the Mississippi, 1988; additional photographs; listing of "American Town Plans" and "European Maps and Plans" owned by Professor Reps; diploma, awards, certificates, and plaques.
Research files on French bastides, research files for a proposed book on medieval and Renaissance city images, transparencies and negatives for published books, and miscellaneous files.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of city and regional planning, Cornell University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Drafts, resource materials, proofs and correspondence concerning Reps's book, Monumental Washington, ca.1967; first drafts, final manuscripts and galley proofs of The Making of Urban America, ca.1965 and Town Planning in Frontier America, ca.1968. Also, five photographs, ca.1865: three albumen prints of the Rochester flood; and two gelatin prints of the Sibley fire, Rochester, New York, collected by Professor Reps. Also notes on Competitors Australian Federal Capital Competition for the book Canberra, 1912; correspondence pertaining to Saint Louis Illustrated; and publications and lectures by Reps. Files for CRP 462.
Research materials and notes for a projected book about planning in the Southeastern United States.
Also, scrapbooks and albums compiled from various trips taken by Professor and Mrs. Reps, and an album from the 2001 symposium commemorating Professor Reps's 50th anniversary at Cornell.
Notes, correspondence, drafts, etc. relating to John Caspar Wild: Painter and Printmaker of Nineteenth-century Urban America, a catalogue raisonné, by John Reps, published by the Missouri Historical Society Press, 2006.
Photographs and articles, also a CD (CD-1387) relating to Gilmore Clarke.
Personal items include photographs; travel diary from England, 1947; interviews with UK planners, 1950-1951 and a 1994 article; negatives of views of French bastides (new towns) used in an exhibition; color transparencies of Cornell views, summer 1986; file "How Lewis Mumford Never Came to Cornell," 1965-1970; correspondence about St. Louis Illustrated, 1985; file on Alex McLean/Landslides for Cities of the Mississippi, 1988; additional photographs; listing of "American Town Plans" and "European Maps and Plans" owned by Professor Reps; diploma, awards, certificates, and plaques.
Research files on French bastides, research files for a proposed book on medieval and Renaissance city images, transparencies and negatives for published books, and miscellaneous files.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Reps, John William.; Reps, John William.; Reps, John William.; Reps, John William.; Reps, John William.; Reps, John William.; Reps, John William.; Clarke, Gilmore D., 1892-1982.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Clarke, Gilmore D., 1892-1982; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University
Subjects:
City planning.; City planning; Travel; Universities and colleges -- Faculty
Places:
Monroe County (N.Y.); Rochester (N.Y.); Washington (D.C.) -- Description and travel.; New York (State) -- Monroe County; New York (State) -- Rochester; Washington (D.C.)
Form and Genre Terms:
Galley proofs.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Pictorial works
INFORMATION FOR USERS
NOTES
See also: Urban Explorer: The John Reps Travel Photographs, which consists of digitized images from this collection.
See also: John Reps Bastides Collection, which consists of digitized images from this collection.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Slides and Photographs
CONTAINER LIST
- Slides and Photographs
  - Travel, lecture, and research slides; Bastides photographs and negatives, 1959-1999 (Box 58)
    American colonial and 19th century town plans and views; Birch views of Philadelphia; Perry's expedition to Japan; Charles Center in Baltimore; John Caspar Wild; Canberra, Australia (1909); illustrations from city atlas of Braun and Hogenberg; 17th century urban views; Sarlat, France; NYC colonial and 19th century plans
  - Travel, lecture, and research slides, 1909-2006 (Box 59)
    Hemel Hempstead; London Plan; Crawley; Harlow; London; US 19th century; Soviet Union (1959, 1965); J.C. Wild's Valley of the Mississippi; Moscow and Leningrad (1990); colonial and 19th century maps and views of US cities; portraits of persons involved in planning in America and foreign countries; modern views of Native American towns in New Mexico; Albuquerque; Helsinki; Stockholm; lecture on Jefferson as city planner; American railroads as founders of towns; American urban land policy; Canal du Midi, Arles to Puy-de-Dome, and Gien
  - US and Canada slides, Undated (Box 71)
    Alabama-Arizona, Western hemisphere (c.1500-1800), Canada, US history, railroads, blighted areas
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 72)
    Arkansas-California
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 73)
    California-Washington D.C.
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 74)
    Washington D.C.-Florida
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 75)
    Florida-Louisiana
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 60)
    Louisiana-Massachusetts
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 61)
    Michigan-Missouri
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 62)
    Missouri-New York
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 63)
    New York
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 64)
    New York-Pennsylvania
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 65)
    Pennsylvania, Puerto Rico, Rhode Island-Texas
  - US state slides, Undated (Box 66)
    Virginia-Wisconsin
  - US and international slides, Undated (Box 67)
    Wisconsin-Wyoming, Cuba, Dominican Republic, Panama, Mexico, Argentina, Chile, Colombia, Uruguay, Sweden, Norway, England, Ireland, Scotland, Belgium, France
  - International slides, Undated (Box 68)
    Spain, Portugal, Germany, Netherlands, Switzerland, Greece, Hungary, Israel, Syria, Turkey, and others
  - Slides, Undated (Box 69)
    Canberra and other plans
  - Slides, Undated (Box 70)
    Lithography, planning, and other topics
  - Lecture slides, Undated (Box 80)
    Reclamation, DC, Mormon towns, St. Louis, New Orleans, Great Plains, Sweden, Norway, Finland, Montobaum, Walter Burney Griffin
  - Lecture slides, Undated (Box 81)
    Cities on Paper, Munster, Vienna, Colonial North America town planning, Gotham grid, town planning on the American Great Plains, Jefferson as town planner
  - Color digital prints, double-matted, Undated (Box 76)
  - Articles and reports, Undated (Box 77)
  - Bastide Exhibition Text Panels, Undated (Box 78)
  - Bastide Exhibition Text Panels, Undated (Box 79)
  - Bastide photographs and negative prints, Undated (Box 82)
  - Bastides photos: Walls and gates, 1966 (Box 82)
  - Bastides photos, 1966 (Box 83)
  - Bastides photos, 1966 (Box 84)
  - Bastides photos, 1966 (Box 85)
  - Bastides photos, 1966 (Box 86)
  - Bastides photos: 6 streets, 1966 (Box 87)
  - Bastides photos: Distant views, 1966 (Box 88)
  - Bastides photos: Squares and arcades, 1966 (Box 89)